-
Speaker 1: And then I realized everything my parents thought they knew about it was wrong. And it was influenced by the media
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): back then. I mean, it looks like a shark. That's cool. And the Porsche snobs won't like it, which is even better, because then you won't become one of them.
Speaker 3: Oh, look at the car I have. Oh, look, I'm in a club. It should be worth more.
-
what's up
Speaker 4: people time to go car shopping Casey style
Speaker 5: so what that basically means is I'm a cheapo but a through-and-through car guy which means I don't like paying
Speaker 6: money for stupid things and I'm basically broke so which is pretty much like most people out there so how are
Speaker 6: do I apply my knowledge and trickery, there's no trickery, to get the sweetest car for the least amount of money? And also, how do you devalue a car, someone asked me. Like, what makes cars worth less than they should be? So, fascinating thing. And this is all going to come in together. So, let's just talk about...
Speaker 6: where you get the greatest deals in the car world. First of all, if you start using all the major buzzword names, you're probably not gonna get a very good deal. But in
Speaker 7: every car mark, there are models of cars that are either completely forgotten by all the glamorous
Speaker 3: collectors and people that like to go to the clubs. "Ooh, look at the car I have. "Ooh, look, I'm in a club. "It should be worth more, ooh." You know, those people that aren't real car people but annoyingly ruin the prices by upping them for
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): everybody.
And
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): there's also the cars that are black sheep where it's like "Oh, well we belong to this club and we've all decided that car is ugly, therefore it is not worth any money."
Speaker 6: Which is also stupid and not real car people and I don't like that. Which is also crazy because I've been around long enough I've seen cars go from just like everybody hated them to now they're cool and chic. So basically the moral of the story is if you're a real car guy and you like a car,
Speaker 6: it's an okay car look past all the BS from everybody else and you might find a really great car that you're gonna love and have a lot of pride in and enjoy and drive that's gonna be spectacular even if the mass populace is too stupid to know it's any good let's talk about what makes a car not valuable okay first of all cars
Speaker 6: that are interesting and attractive to people, collector cars, et cetera, they have a
Speaker 7: certain utility, okay? In the sense of like, how drivable are they? They're reasonably comfortable to drive. Are they fast? Do they stop well? Do they handle well? Do they cost a fortune to repair? Are they relatively easy to repair? That comes into it. But the utility isn't the greatest factor 'cause there are a lot of cars out there that are just cantankerous, delicate,
Speaker 7: overly complex
Speaker 9: disasters which are worth too much money i.e like my old coontosh if i still had it it was a cantankerous delicate pain in the butt that wasn't
Speaker 7: that fast but i loved it anyway and then the prices went through the moon that's that's a topic for another time but i'm going to tell you the
Speaker 10: truth on what makes cars valuable and what makes certain cars not valuable and the world's not going to like
Speaker 6: to hear it
Speaker 6: because there's some nasty subjects there. What makes interesting sports cars valuable has everything to do with money and class. It has everything to do with fantasy. And it has everything to do with how much does it make your loins burn. Let's be honest, okay? If it's
Speaker 7: fast and exciting and visceral and colorful and mean, then it's making your loins burn, okay? And it's exciting to drive. Like an F40 is a badass visceral machine, okay? My Dodge Viper, badass visceral machine. But...
Speaker 7: An F40 is worth a heck of a lot more and a Viper is not worth that much money. So why? You know, production numbers come into play with some things. But the truth of the matter is, rarity doesn't have that much to do with the value of a car. You know, I think they made, what, 30 Ferrari 250 GTOs? Oh, big deal. I've owned race cars and things where there were less of them than that. It's
Speaker 6: not about rarity so much. The other thing that drives me nuts I just have to throw out there is all the muscle car guys like, well, if you add up all the different combinations of this here car, the engine spec, the funny houndstooth,
Speaker 6: upholstery on the interior this color that color and this year they only made seven like this I'm like big deal dude they made 30,000
of
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): that car that year like that's not rare I can just get another one and dude it up like that to match it so that's not real rare but when people get an interesting car they want
Speaker 7: a fantasy and
if the
Speaker 7: fantasy is worth it that much to them they're gonna spend money to get it and a lot of those fantasies relate to do I think I'm rich
or
Speaker 7: Do I think I'm some sort of cool actor like Steve McQueen or James Dean or something like that, right? Like,
you know,
Speaker 12: the bullet Mustang? It's not that special of a car. You can build a zillion of those for less, but oh, because it's Steve McQueen and Steve McKean beat the crap out of it. It's worth a ton of money. Stupid. I mean, for that one person, whatever,
Speaker 13: but come on. Let's write our own history for these cars, right?
be
Speaker 13: an individual
Speaker 6: the other one is if it's like oh it's so chic everybody had this was rich and had many servants and peasants and i want to imagine i'm like that too that makes the cars worth a bunch of money which is silly so conversely what makes cars not worth a bunch of money well don't
hate me for
Speaker 6: saying this but it's true racial things come
Speaker 7: into play
Speaker 7: If the people with money that decide car is worth a bunch of money and those clubs and such decide that a car is liked by a demographic of people that they thumb the nose down at, then they're not going to like it. If a car seems kind of like Southern or Redneck, or in their opinion, it's not going to be
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): worth as much, which I think is what frankly hurts Corvette C4s.
Speaker 7: Which is stupid, because that is the ultimate best deal in the sports car world, period. Corvette C4s. But you have to get
Speaker 6: over yourself.
Speaker 6: Because people look at it and go, well, it's just gray-haired old balding men in a boring club, or it's rednecks. And, you know, both of those have a certain amount of truth to them, but are just mean and derogatory, and we need
to get
Speaker 6: over it, because those are great cars.
Speaker 15: Okay? Oh, I don't like them, because the interiors are kind of plastic. So what?
So
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): what? It's a cool car.
Speaker 17: So...
You
Speaker 17: know, and then of course there's cars like there's certain Maseratis and things that,
Speaker 9: you know, cost a fair amount to fix or can be a little cantankerous. And people like to knock them because they weren't famous, they don't fit some fantasy for them, and they just beat up on them because you're actually buying
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): like an Italian exotic car and it takes
Speaker 19: maintenance. So then they just decide it's not worth anything.
And then it's
Speaker 19: just absolutely so silly. As an example, I really like
Speaker 20: 1980s Porsches. I love 944s. I even kind of like 924s.
Speaker 19: 928s are kind of neat.
Speaker 19: But the Porsche world is the ultimate world of just like snobs, oh my god, and it's not even like good snobs, it's just snobs.
Speaker 12: It's like, "We like alcohols to be air-cooled and sound like sewing machines, even though it's been the same body style since the 60s." Like, great.
They
Speaker 12: made a ton of those things. Let's make those worth a ton of money. We don't like it if it has water. We don't like the engine in the front. That's redneck like some sort of American muscle car. It was originally a Volkswagen. The 924 was to be a Volkswagen, and that's a peasant car.
Speaker 21: do you see the snobbery that comes out to make cars worth a lot of money so another car that's just the best value is a 944 such a cool car i love them they're perfectly balanced they're pointing they look good they were in cool 80s pop culture they're just fun little cars they're
not that
Speaker 21: fast but as an example the 944 turbo was faster around a road course than the 911 turtle or 930
Speaker 15: turbo i think back in the day so snob on it but porsche people like we have to have air - Is that super cool?
Speaker 15: engines with the engine in a weird place like some sort of weird pre-war Tatra or like Ferdinand's Porsche's original people for the car for the people
Speaker 21: big deal and then you know I just I hate snobbery on cars I'm just a car guy and
I
The
Speaker 21: thing about it is that's neat, and I'm in car
Speaker 22: shopping, and
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): actually I bought a car today, so this is not going to
be
Speaker 10: in order, but that's okay. We're going to shop anyway, and then I'll show you what I bought. But I
had a
Speaker 10: huge moment where I realized I feel
Speaker 21: amazing about my purchase. I love the car. I think it's so great, and I feel just as good about this car as I would if I bought like $100,000 something or other. I've lost it after forever. But the thing costs peanuts. It was peanuts.
but I think
Speaker 21: it's great. It takes me back to a cool time. It's a great
Speaker 1: built car, has a neat design. It's got history. I can't wait to drive it. I can't wait to show you guys. I can't wait to work on it and fix it up and make it better, which I think we all enjoy. You know, fixing up a car is a great thing. It's kind of like,
Speaker 1: It's cathartic, right? You feel better about yourself to bring something back and give it new life. Especially if in some way you connect to that car. And maybe, spoiler alert for mine, it's from the 80s. It's just a funny thing. So there's so many great cars out there you can really just appreciate as a car guy.
And I
Speaker 9: love that nowadays on the internet there's cool things like Radwood, where people are embracing the wackiness of old that people used to hate 80s stuff forever.
Speaker 9: As a perfect example, I should do a video on this if you guys like. The DeLorean is the most misunderstood automobile. And I say automobile because forget about the company
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): and the guy. Just forget about it right now. The DeLorean car is the most misunderstood car of the 20th century, period. And it
was the
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): most amazing case study for me as a kid because my baby boomer parents and all baby boomers, and I'm not knocking them, I'm just using that generation, all were slanted by the media to despise that car and think it's a junk lemon. When in fact, that's not true remotely.
Speaker 1: whatsoever I got a buddy it's got like 250,000 miles on one I have daily driven two DeLoreans through all four seasons in Ohio snow everything I love the car I would daily drive one any day of the year
Speaker 12: great car but the baby boomers ruined it and they all think it's junk and the people like what's a junk car you ask them you ever driven one
no and
Speaker 12: it's all missed so back then was a great learning lesson for me when I wanted to learn about the car and find out if they were any good because I thought I wanted to own one as a kid
and
And
Speaker 12: then I realized everything my parents thought they
Speaker 1: knew about it was wrong. And it was influenced by the media back then. So that's a perfect example of how stupid things can ruin the value of a car for so long. But for us car guys, it's a perfect opportunity for us to have great fun. So let's look for some cars. So I got my computer out, obviously, like people do late in the evening. And as you can see, I am on Facebook. Because right now, I think Facebook Marketplace
is probably
Speaker 1: the best place to get good deals. Okay, Casey, you old geezer, work the internet. Let's go. Marketplace. All right, so I'm going to start with what I know. Now,
Speaker 17: typically, if I'm going to go back in the day and I'm going to try to find a car I can afford, I'm thinking Porsche 944. They make great all-year-round cars. They're really hard to rust. Porsche galvanized the bodies, I think, and they got great weight distribution,
Speaker 20: and I like them. Corvette C4s are great cars, but I don't know. I don't think they're that great in the winter. I had one in and when are there?
Speaker 20: And maybe like a 928 or something.
Speaker 10: But you know what? I also came to myself, you know, I should look at some Japanese cars from the 80s too. Because I haven't had one of those.
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): And they're kind of cool, right? The first gen MR2s, those old Supers from the 80s. I drove one of those back in the day. That was cool. All right. So as you can see, I was out of here looking for stuff. I've
Speaker 1: got some C4 Corvettes popping up. And I'm just going to start right here.
Speaker 1: C4 Corvette. Ask her. I'll just go to Corvette. You can't really type in C4 Corvette because people don't really search them by body styles. But as an
Speaker 9: example here, so C4s, they're pretty much all the same. I mean, by the time it got to the 90s, they changed the dash up so it had, like, analog ages instead of the Death Star dash that was all, like, that multicolored LCD.
the
Speaker 17: better engine made more power um it also had the six-speed manual if you can get it and i don't like automatic sports cars there's some smoking deals on automatic sports cars from back in the day but i don't really like them it's
Speaker 9: kind of hard to find a corvette in manual because the people that bought them were old and tired and remember drag racing in the 60s and thought automatic is cool
Speaker 24: it's
not
so
Speaker 9: anyway it's harder to find a Corvette that's manual and the ones you want to get are going to be the six speed I think that was somewhere in the area of I can't remember if it was like 89 90 or 91 probably like 1990 ish was the first six speed Corvette that's I had one of those they were great the 80s Corvettes had the four plus three which is a four speed transmission with overdrive that you could actually wait in the top three gears so it's kind of weird I guess it's okay I'm not too wild about that
Speaker 9: Also, a Corvette C4 is the
Speaker 7: best car to cut apart to make a custom out of it. Hate me if you want Corvette people, it's true. They're a great smoking deal and you can make
Speaker 17: awesome customs out of it. So let's just look see what we got here. Okay, 85 Corvette coupe, two-door, I'm just gonna open this up.
Speaker 10: Maybe, if it works. They're asking $3,500 bucks! It's got torque thrust wheels on it, looks kind of cool, not really the right period. It's red, it's got a targa roof.
Speaker 10: Uh, 91,000 miles, paints a little faded, uh, but
Speaker 21: you know, probably a half decent car. Good starter for restoration, uses everyday driver must see for yourself. Yeah,
whatever, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 21: Okay. So it's got the clear roof and it paints a little faded. You could probably buff that out. Maybe
wet
Woman 25: sand it, um, or, you know, screw it, plastic dip it or something. I don't know. Or paint it, learn how to paint. It's, they're asking 3,500 bucks. You could probably get it for three grand. It's a red Corvette.
I
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): mean, come on, I had a Corvette C4, it had like 110,000 miles, it was a fine car. You can go down to AutoZone or whatever and get parts for it. Gosh, it's just such,
Speaker 1: it's exciting to see this. And frankly, I hope the prices of these things stay down. And I'm going to beat up all the cars I like right now. Yeah,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): oh, you bunch of snobs out there, this here's a C4 Corvette, it's only for rednecks. You got to drive a car hard in this.
Speaker 26: What you need to do is you need to join my really old gray-haired club where we drive five miles an hour at all times. Okay, car guys,
Speaker 7: you hate me? I just saved you forever so these car prices don't go way up and you can actually enjoy them.
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): You're welcome. All right,
what else
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): here? Look,
Woman 25: $4,500, $4,000. I mean, come on. There's bunches of them. They're all over the place. Pick your poison. It's great fun. You can go check them out. It's a Chevy small block. I mean...
Woman 25: people give those things away practically i just i think
Speaker 1: that's a great place c5 corvettes are a good value too but i really want to talk about things that are very affordable like less than five grand so that's a place to start uh c4 corvette's not really that great in winter the tires aren't that wide and you can get all season tires for them which are
Speaker 1: But keep in mind, it's a harder sprung car. Not a lot
Speaker 19: of weight transfer. It is rear-wheel drive, so you need to be good at being
Speaker 1: able to drift and hold controlled slides and things like that. But it can be done. I've done it. You know, back in the day, it wasn't great. I lived in a small town.
Speaker 1: It's not ideal to be in a C4 Corvette if you hit the highway in snow, but depending on where you live and what you choose to do, depending on how you work and what you need to rely on it for, it's a very doable thing. And even if it's your secondary car and you work hard, maybe flip the things, I don't know, restore some bicycles and sell 'em, you too could afford a C4 Corvette. So, next on the list, Porsche 944.
I
Speaker 1: love 'em, I've always loved them since I was a kid. Porsche 944's evolved from, if I'm not mistaken, the Porsche 924, which originally was a car that was going to be made for Volkswagen and or Audi in the 1970s. And then Volkswagen pulled the plug, they're like, "We don't need a..." They didn't need a sports car. And they were powered by the Audi engine
Speaker 17: and they Porsche badge and
Speaker 9: that's what it was. So the 944,
Speaker 9: Grew out of the 924 it got the fender flares, which I just think look amazing it reminds me of all the Cars from the 80s racing like Daytona and whatnot So they look tough. They look good. They were in a bunch of cool stuff
TVs
Speaker 17: and movies in the 80s, but it got an engine developed by Porsche's four-cylinder It's slanted and it's got two balance shafts in it. So it's a little smooth That's why I has two timing belts one for the camshaft one for the balance shafts and I
Speaker 17: If I'm not mistaken, the Porsche 944 engine is basically derived
Speaker 9: off of half of the architecture from a 928, where it's pretty similar. And they
do have
Speaker 9: electronic fuel injection versus
Speaker 5: Bosch KJetronic, which is nice, makes more power. And I just like them a lot. People used to freak out, oh, water pumps and timing belts. It's not that bad. I mean, I can do that in my driveway, even without the tensioning tool. If you're a mechanic
Speaker 9: that's worth your salt and you can actually feel the timing belts, It's like,
Speaker 9: like on this Ducati or something, you can do it. In fact, you need like a couple thin wrenches, I think, for the timing belt. But frankly, one of them I used was thick sheet metal and I cut it with some shears and made my own wrench. Like, it's not that hard, it's just not that hard. But if you've never done it before, you'd probably want somebody with a little bit of expertise there. So I love these cars, they're not super fast, it's not
a
Speaker 1: car to beat on, it's not a burnout car. In fact, 944s,
Speaker 7: if they have the original clutch,
Speaker 7: When you test drive it, find out if it has a lot of driveling lash. When you accelerate and then slow down, does it
Speaker 9: lag and then buck? Does it do that? That's a sign that the clutch is blown out because instead of having springs like a normal clutch in the middle, it's rubber.
Speaker 9: So if you do like I did and be a nice guy and teach your ex-dumb girlfriend to drive stick shift in it, she'll ruin the clutch. It'll
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): still drive fine, but she'll blow out the center. Or anybody learning to drive stick, no, I'm not being sexist. It just happens I was being nice to that girlfriend at the time and she
Speaker 27: trashed my Porsche
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): clutch. So
Speaker 17: anyway, so don't do that.
Speaker 17: it's not a it's not a drag racing car you can do that with the corvette if you if that's your thing but a 944 perfect car for the street perfect car for light track
Speaker 1: days you can autocross you have a great time and there's loads of parts available there's lots of cars that are junk so if you need an engine you need something off it you can get parts cars so the trouble with 944s are the prices are kind of all
Speaker 17: over the board
And
Speaker 17: it's getting harder to find a nice one because a lot of them got trashed by
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): people that could afford it and thought they were cool because they had a Porsche. They're like, oh, I fancy I have a Porsche. I'm going to ruin this little car and drive it to the bar like an idiot and sideswipe
Speaker 6: somebody. Oh, God. But
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): there's still good cars out there. Don't be afraid of mileage as much on a 944 depending on the owner. I've seen
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): 944 as well under the 100,000 miles that are nice, but you got to know. Um...
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): If I'm not mistaken, the cylinders are aluminum with like a Nicosil coating or something. So if it's smoking, you might want to avoid it because just you're not going to rebuild that engine like a small block Chevy. You want to kind of find one that's about as nice as you reasonably can, that runs good. You can do little things, you can make the body better, but there's some things that just you don't fix up so easily.
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): And since it's a car not worth a ton of money, you don't, you wanna get a car that is a good value. So the time and effort and money you put into it,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): you have a better chance of getting back or retaining the value rather than buying a basket case for a couple of grand that is gonna take forever to make better and it's never gonna be as good a car as the other one. So something to think
Speaker 1: about. Also, I kind of find it annoying the people that just trash 'em or rally 'em or think they're cool 'cause I got a cheap Porsche, I'm gonna beat the crap out of it. Well, you're an ass and not a car guy and a jerk.
So
Speaker 1: don't do that. It's a perfectly nice car. Sell it to somebody who might care, like a young person out there. Okay, so let's look at one here. Here's an 86 944. It is that kind of champagne color, which a lot of people didn't like, but has grown on me. Ooh, that's got kind of a nice interior. Now, here's a perfect example. $3,200, 91,000 miles. Beautiful seats. Everything about it's nice, except for
one
Speaker 17: thing. It's automatic, which ruins it for me. But...
If
Speaker 17: you don't mind
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): driving an automatic 944, you can get smoking deals on cars that usually are very nice because they were automatic and not driven hard. All
Speaker 9: right. Now, the trouble with 944s are now these Porsche geeks are in horrible dealerships,
Speaker 6: both small and large, are trying to inflate the prices of them. Because they're like, we need another Porsche to inflate the prices of like all these other Porsches. Let's ruin the 944 for everybody.
Speaker 6: So that's what they're trying to do. You can still buy nice 944s
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): for $4,000 to $6,000 or $7,000 all the time. But it's harder and you got to look. If you go on eBay, all the prices there
Speaker 20: are inflated. People want like $8,000, $10,000, $12,000, $15,000. And it's just like, get over yourself. And you also see a listing
of a
Speaker 20: number of dealerships.
Speaker 20: And it's like, get a new job. All you're doing is
Speaker 9: inflating all the prices of cars and ruining it for car guys everywhere. I hate that. Let's see what else we got
Speaker 1: here. I did see a while back ago, there was a 944 Turbo on here. Now, Turbo prices have gone up quite a bit. Yeah, here it is. They're asking seven grand for this one. 71,000 miles is burgundy. It's got kind of the twist looking wheels going on. Now, it's got an issue. It says car turns, but does not turn on. I have audio starting issue. Cannot upload it here. Clean car, clean title. For seven grand with that kind of mileage,
Speaker 1: for a 944 turbo with this, Miles, and its stick shift, pretty decent seats, pretty decent interior. Gosh, like even if it broke a timing belt and you had to take the head off and have the head rebuilt and the valves done, if it didn't like bust the valves off, you could spend a little effort to work on this and come out ahead. For me right now, that's out of my
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): budget, but for maybe one of you, this is gonna be a great car. You're welcome.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): you've got to be more careful here's a car this is an
Speaker 21: example of one I think that's probably been maintained well they're asking 7,500 bucks for it little high ish the reason I say that's got
Speaker 17: 143,000 miles but this person the way they write about it you can tell they really care they they gave you a basic brief description about this car they told you all the great things that are on here
Speaker 17: you know of things they've done
Speaker 20: to make it better they've powder coated the phone dials white i think that's a really great handsome combination i think it just looks well they photographed it nicely the paints they've taken a lot of pride it's got nice sport seats they look great it's
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): got a roll bar in it it's got the old dashboard oh that's all that they're talking my language i like the old dashboard uh the old dashboard pre-85 has the round gauges that's
Speaker 29 (lower-pitched voice): kind of my thing now that's interesting those look like the gauges out of a 924 because they have red needles instead of yellow like in a 944.
Speaker 29 (lower-pitched voice): that's weird
Speaker 1: anyway they're asking a bit of money for it but it looks like they really took care of it so if you call this person they probably know everything about it it's a body's beautiful the interior
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): is beautiful it's
Speaker 17: got nice tasteful add-ons you know and it doesn't smoke or make any hateful noises the suspensions tight and drives great
Speaker 17: It's probably a perfectly good car So you got to decide what do you want and what kind of love do you want? They made a lot of 944 so in this example I might be willing to spend more money on a car with more miles because it looks beautiful and it's probably has a great owner the other reason I like simple
Speaker 19: cars like this is
Speaker 19: They're less prone to braking once you get it worked out and you maintain them nicely They don't have all this crap that glitches like the Porsche bodies don't rush you can maintain them And the other thing nice about getting an older sports car like this You always have like
Speaker 1: a cult community and a cult following Which means basically every problem the car has ever had or will ever had has already happened Somebody's talked about
Speaker 29 (lower-pitched voice): it on the internet and
Speaker 10: has a fix
Speaker 10: Which means the world is your treasure trove. So if you can't work on a car, just have a good service shop you trust. It's all about a calculated risk. And I can tell
Speaker 17: you from my entire lifetime experience, I have always ended up so much better off by driving a cool,
Speaker 19: cult car like this that's in good condition, maintaining it myself, just looking after that, caring about the car. That's important.
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): Rather than just losing money hand over fist on some boring, stupid new car that's going to break where you get stuck dealing with dealerships that hate
Speaker 30: you and everybody and themselves. Okay.
Speaker 30: right on. Let's look at Porsche 928s. They
are a
Speaker 1: funny car. They're bigger. They're heavier than a 944, but they're a grand touring kind of car. It's not a car you're going to throw around necessarily. You could. And their V8, that's kind of neat. But the prices are all over the board. The later ones that are making more power,
Speaker 7: Porsche people have decided, the snobs
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): have decided to make them worth more money. So $30,000, $50,000 for crap like that. But the early ones, Maybe the single camshaft rather than the four
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): camshaft ones.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): they're simpler the five speeds if you can find them a lot of them are automatic which is kind of a drag uh are
Speaker 20: cheaper let's look at one here here's one in michigan 127 000 miles it's a bit much so we'll see what it is it's got the little wing it's black uh they're asking 4500 bucks for
it
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): doesn't
Speaker 31: look that shiny
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): maybe they just cleaned
it off
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): bad and i also judge by the you know how nice is the car going to be when the garage is a total mess right you just you look at those things i'm not picking on the person but i am utilizing it to
Speaker 20: think so 4 500 bucks it could be an okay car it's got a lot of miles okay what else we got here let's
look at this
Speaker 20: one 6750 6750
Speaker 17: now allegedly this car has 32 000 miles which is really low
Speaker 17: But this guy's saying new tires and brakes, belts and hoses, plugs and wires, water pump, timing belt, fuel pump, intake boots, fuel accumulator, slave cylinder, runs great. Interior needs some work. All right, let's look at this picture here. It's
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): cool. It's good color. Looks very shiny. It doesn't say repaint. That might lead me to believe it could be a low mileage car
Speaker 17: like that.
And
Speaker 17: judging from the fact that it's got all this work done to it might be a car that got pulled out of a garage from long-term storage. So something like this would come down to how well it was caretake and looked after. Is it smoking? Does it have any big issues? Has it been hit? Is it rotted out? The seats are going bad here. The cloth just does over time and the dash cracks. You can have that upholstered relatively easily, but that's going to be a cost to do it right. That seat's covered up.
Speaker 17: So we'll see on that one that
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): that could be a could be a winner. It's a little more money You don't know how much you can bring them down in price and that's assuming he doesn't have any other big horrible issues Here's another 928 85 hundred and sixty four thousand miles an automatic, you know that at least tells you these cars can drive for a long long long time It says runs great 32 valve 35 year old not perfect, and that's it. It looks beautiful. It's all polished wheels are polished
Speaker 21: That's cool. I mean
Speaker 21: Isn't that neat? They can have a car that's that chic and interesting looking that you can put that many miles on. I mean, it looks like a shark. That's cool. And the Porsche snobs won't like it, which is even
Speaker 10: better because then you won't become one of them. Okay. If you're in the Porsche club, I like you well enough too. It's
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): just not my scene. I would rather be driving and it's fun to make fun of you guys. So hate me.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): You're making fun of me. Be my guest. I'm on the internet. So those are some good deals there. Let me try out some Japanese cars. Let's see if I don't know if
Speaker 17: there's any Mr. Twos.
Speaker 17: generations second generations are neat i rode around with a buddy but i
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): just there's something i like about the funky folded paper origami look of the first ones i don't care if they're slower and more cantankerous they're i think they're just fine they're great cars harder to find a nice one they can rot gosh not much came up
what does
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): this guy want fostoria ooh both tops or best offer 4200 bucks looks like it's sat around a lot 100 000 miles
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): it could be okay yeah well i guess they really took care of that car as a table uh i'd be into that i don't know if i want to drive in the winter in ohio because i feel like it would rot to the ground with salt uh german cars do pretty well uh in the salt in the winter in the winter so that's why i'm kind of partial
to that let's
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): type in super for fun now i know you guys will lose your mind if i don't type in bmw so i'll do that too
all right these uh
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): is this 91
This
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): generation of Supers kind of neat. I drove one way back when. I test drove it. My dad was snobbing on Japanese
cars.
Speaker 33: He influenced me too much with cars back
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): when. Now this is interesting too. So a decent Scirocco, they're starting to want money too. Here's an 88, used to have one
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): of these. Mine was black, 16 valve. That's a cool car. That one's really nice. That one's pretty darn nice. They want eight grand for it, which is, you know, a bit of money, but if
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): you got a nice Scirocco,
the
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): seats are probably garbage and these pedals are stupid those are those really cheap pedal covers that people put on because they want to feel like a race car driver even though it makes the pedals crap and they come loose and then your feet
Speaker 20: get caught on them yeah I don't think that's an $8,000 car sorry dude hey
Speaker 5: check this out you guys it's a Harlequin Jetta from the 90s it's actually supposed to be like that from the factory I don't
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): know if that's actually the factory car I think Donut Media or somebody recently did something on the Harlequin
But
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): yeah, $5,500 bucks. If you want to always be remembered, that's the car for you. I saw this earlier and I thought maybe I should do this and I don't know if I could bring myself to try that every day. I
Speaker 12: mean, I really like it. But the problem, this is America in the Midwest. People are gonna look at that, what in the hell? What in the hell kind of freak show clown car is that? How many clowns can you fit in your car? How many dumb jokes can I tell you in five minutes? That's what would happen.
Look
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): at those sweet seats. This car is awesome.
It's
Speaker 10: got like the Tartan seats.
Yes. All right, let's
Speaker 10: look up BMWs, youseguys.
Oh, and then
Speaker 30: Beamer people got all snobby and made the BMW M3s from the 80s worth a ton of money. Get life. They're not that great. You guys just need to relax. Oh, what's this?
A
Speaker 10: 1998 M3 for... how much? 3,200 bucks? What?
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): 173,000 miles, got a lot of miles. Headlights
Speaker 20: are all faded, or foggy looking. Interior looks okay, you could probably clean it up. Brake pad light, check engine light, airbag
Speaker 30: light. Yeah, you know, it's 3, 200 bucks. You know, someday these goobers are gonna like lose their mind, like, I need a 90s M3, let's make it worth too much money. I don't know, maybe not, I hope they don't.
Speaker 30: I just like real people to be able to afford stuff because we're not making more money Why
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): are these cars all worth too much money because people are getting loans. That's the problem
One of the
Speaker 35: problems. There's lots of problems.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): I'm an old man, and I'm gonna say old man things and rant things cost more Back in my day. I used
to
Speaker 36: buy things cheaper. Well,
Speaker 30: whatever I still think I can drive old cars year-round because we did back in my day All right
Speaker 30: Well, start looking, guys. Tell
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): me what deals you find. This is what I've seen so far, but I am going to get an old car back for my day. I'm going to drive it. I'm going to fix it up, and it's going to be great on YouTube. Yes! Lamborghini builds. Lame. Who could afford that? I'm going to do a real build with you guys. We'll do it together. We'll go for a cruise.
All right, so
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): maybe
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): help me out, see if you guys find any deals, or, you know, get them for yourself. I've had my time, right? And if you guys get inspired to find any great cars and have a good experience,
Speaker 30: I hope you share it. And we get to, I don't know, go for a cruise sometime in the future or something. But I'm going to buy a car. I don't know what it'll be.
Maybe I'll
Speaker 19: just go nuts. I don't even know. But in the meantime, please like, comment, and subscribe. And I'll see you next time.
We'll see you next time.